ANTONIO ALGABA OSUNA

Aspiring Frontend Web Developer

Location: London • Phone: 07831230339 • Email: antonioalgabaosuna@gmail.com Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/antonio-algaba-osuna-448bb43b/ GitHub: https://github.com/AntonioAlgaba

Professional Profile

Aspiring Front End Developer with a year of self-taught coding experience backed up by a recently completed 16 weeks, intensive coding Bootcamp. I have been upskilled in JavaScript ES6, HTML, CSS, React, and Node.js, after making the decision to career shift from a successful 9 years in the hospitality industry.

Having worked for 9 years in the hospitality industry in different roles and most recently in corporate hospitality in law firms, I made the decision in Summer 2022 to change career into something I have always enjoyed, and that's coding. The recent Bootcamp has been tough and very much a full-time undertaking, which I have managed alongside my full time job. I am an A grade student, averaging 97% on my Bootcamp course work, and have also been continuing the learning. As I hope you can see I'm a self-starter, a multitasker and I like to think I get on with everyone I work with. I'm now motivated and energised by getting stuck into my first official developer role.

Core Skills

- HTML5
- CSS3
- JavaScript ES6
- Node
- React
- Git and GitHub

- Object-Oriented Programming
- Deployment
- Agile Methodologies
- API's
- Adaptability and responsiveness
- Effective time management

Projects

Portfolio - https://github.com/AntonioAlgaba/Portfolio - https://antonioalgaba.github.io/Portfolio/ Still working on it

- Portfolio with some of my projects that I've done during the bootcamp.
- HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, React JS, Tailwind CSS.

FitMax - https://github.com/AntonioAlgaba/FitMax - https://earnest-brioche-0d496b.netlify.app/ Final group project.

- FitMax is a webapp which aims to display the most effective workout videos for each body part. It also allows you to calculate different metrics for your health (BMI, Daily Calories, Body Fat, Ideal weight)
- HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, React JS, Tailwind CSS, Material Tailwind, Bootstrap, API Servers (Third Party API'S)

README-generator / https://github.com/AntonioAlgaba/README-generator

- Node app generating a professional README. When you run node index.js, the application uses the inquirer package to prompt you in the command line with a series of questions.
- Node js, JavaScript.

Team-Profile-Generator - https://github.com/AntonioAlgaba/Team-Profile-Generator. First group project.

- Working Node.js command-line application that takes in information about employees on a software engineering team and generates an HTML webpage that displays summaries for each person.
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node js,

PlanMyDinnerMovie - https://github.com/AntonioAlgaba/PlanMyDinnerMovie - https://antonioalgaba.github.io/PlanMyDinnerMovie/

- Plan My Dinner is a search engine that enables you to find the perfect recipe using the ingredients you have at home. Thousands of recipes are made available, all you do is type in the contents of your fridge. Plan My Dinner will even suggest a cocktail to go with it! And also it will suggest a movie just entering a simple word.
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, AJAX, JQuery, Boostrap

Work-Day-Scheduler - https://github.com/AntonioAlgaba/Work-Day-Scheduler - https://antonioalgaba.github.io/Work-Day-Scheduler/

- Daily scheduler app that displays the current day, time and a textarea for each hour what is changing according with the time. It stores data in localSotarage and retrieves it when refresh the page.
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, moment.js

Employment History

Apr 2022 - Present Wilson Vale at Taylor Wessing London Concierge Manager

In my current role as Concierge Manager, I act as deputy to the General Manager and also provide support to the Hospitality and Events Manager. My role requires flexibility and efficiency in order to cover multiple roles when necessary and meet the needs of the departments. My current role includes;

- Building solid, professional relationships with all clients and key stakeholders by being approachable, flexible and attentive in fulfilling customer needs.
- Reception duties and being the first point of contact for the client.
- Regularly monitor customer feedback and produce suitable action plans based on the results.
- Support the General Manager in co-ordinating and managing the recruitment and selection process.

- Support all staff in teams linked to service delivery; improve communication and cohesive work across the departments, facilitate and lead team meetings. Induct and monitor performance of new staff.
- Monitor stock and budget, in support of the company's wider financial targets.
- Weekly planning with the Executive Chef regarding client profiles and manage events (fine dining, canapes), when required.

Oct 2019 – May 2022 Gibson, Dunn and Crutcher LLP Hospitality coordinator-London

Sep 2018 – Oct 19 Baxterstorey at Addleshaw Goddard LLP Hospitality assistant – London

Apr 2016 – Sep 2018 Compass Group at KPMG Customer Services Assistant – London

Education

• November 2022 - March 2023

Skills Bootcamp in Front-End Web Development & UX. University of Birmingham UK

• September 2012 – June 2013

Master's in integrated quality, Environmental and Health and Safety Management System. San Pablo's University, Spain.

September 2002 – September 2008

Bachelor's Degree in Biology, University of Cordoba, Spain